but Yeltsin, Yeltsin, in ninety-three, signed a decree on transferring Crimea to Ukraine, that
подписал Да что Крым передать Украине то
is, until the ninety-third year. It was
есть до девяносто третьего года Это был
Crimea that was in Russia, so in the ninety-
Крым был в России так вот а В девяносто
third, this is not Crimea, but Yeltsin signed a
третьем этот не Крым а Ельцин подписал
decree on the transfer of Crimea to Ukraine from the
указ о передаче Крыма в Украину с
ninety-third year. So what?  vyzh
девяносто третьего года Ну и что выж
decree A good Despite the fact that he
указ А хорошо Несмотря на то что он все
had all the powers by right as the president to
полномочия имел по праву как президент
do this, no referendum was held And
это делать референдума не проводилось А
in this year, as you yourself said
в дет году Как вы сами сказали
in the party, almost everyone
в ком партии чуть ли не все
voted for the fact that it was not worth
проголосовали за то что не стоит было
doing this, that Crimea belongs to  to the
этого делать его что Крым принадлежит по
law of
праву
Russia
России
Hello Good evening I'm from the city of
Здравствуйте Добрый вечер я из города
Khmelnitsky Where are you from? I'm from the
Хмельницкий Вы откуда Я из
Krasnodar Territory and how do you communicate and
Краснодарского края а чем вы общаетесь
on different topics, for the most part
да раз на разные темы по большей части
such
такие
mundane mundane
мирские мирские
vile
мерзкие
these not vile mundane And I
текие не мерзкие мирские А мне мерзкие
think disgusting topics, well, in short, what are you already
темы думаю ну вот короче что такое уже
saying to people's faces?  on vile topics
говоришь людям в лицо на мерзкие темы
you speak rudely vile
говоришь жесть мерзкие
standards understood everything rudely and whose Crimea Do you
мерки понял всё жесть а чей Крым Как ты
think
считаешь
what do you think whose
что как ты считаешь чей
Crimea um rightfully belongs to Russia by
Крым гм по праву принадлежит России по
what right
какому праву
would it be transferred to
бы передан
Ukraine stop initially this is
Украине стоп изначально это
when under Yeltsin under A understood under
когда при ельцине при А понял при
Yeltsin that is, Yeltsin transferred Crimea to
ельцине то есть Ельцин передал Крым
Ukraine
Украине в каком
I don’t remember in what year Well, approximately, you
году не помню Ну приблизительно Ты же
know in what years Yeltsin lived and
знаешь Ельцин в каких годах жил
ruled. Well, he would have been elected president twice, so well,
правил Так ну он два раза президент так
in the late eighties,
избра так так ну в конце восьмидесятых
most likely, well, when the Soviet Union
скорее всего ну когда Советский Союз
collapsed and you had the country of
развалился и у вас появилась страна
Russia, the first day, then let’s do this
Росси дено дено первом то давай так
Yeltsin gave Crimea to Ukraine clues
Ельцин передал Крым Украине подсказки
four options ninety-one
четыре варианта девяносто первый
ninety-second ninety-third or
девяносто второй девяносто третий или
ninety-four In what
девяносто четвёртый В каком
year in one of these what will I
году в одном из этих что я буду
guess you just tell me
угадывать вы просто мне скажите
Remind my memory, so to speak,
Напомните память мою так сказать
refresh
освежите
you remember when Yeltsin shot up your
помнишь когда Ельцин расстрелял у вас
White
Белый
House and from tanks what year  what year,
дом да из танков какой год какой год я
of course, I was not present then not with In
конечно не присутствовал тогда не с В
what year did he
каком году он
shoot the ninety Trey ninety-
расстрелял че девяносто Трей девяносто
third year and you know why he
третий год а и знаешь из-за чего он
shot the White
расстрелял танками Белый
House with tanks the Communist Party was there Well why
дом там компартия находилась Ну почему
Yes why Because Yeltsin in the children's year
Да почему Потому что Ельцин в дет году
signed a decree that  give Crimea to
подписал указ о том чтобы отдать Крым
Ukraine and the Communist Party and those who were other
Украине а компартия и те кто были другие
deputies they were against they held a
депутаты они были против они сделали
rally canceled Yeltsin’s decision Yeltsin
митинг отменили решение Ельцина Ельцин
took Tanks and shot the
взял подогнал Танки и расстрелял
parliament This is your
парламент Вот это ваша
story but Yeltsin Yeltsin signed in ninety-
история но Ельцин же Ельцин В девяносто
three Yes, what to hand over Crimea to
третьем подписал Да что Крым передать
Ukraine, that is, until the ninety-third
Украине то есть до девяносто третьего
year  It was Crimea, it was in Russia, and so
года Это был Крым был в России так вот
in the ninety-third year, this is not Crimea, but
а В девяносто третьем кры этот не Крым а
Yeltsin signed a decree on the transfer of Crimea to
Ельцин подписал указ о передачи Крыма в
Ukraine and from the ninety-third year, well,
Украину и с девяносто третьего года Ну и
what the hell are you doing, it’s so good, Despite the fact
что вы ж ука так а хорошо Несмотря на то
that he had all the powers by right as
что он все полномочия имел по праву как
the president to do this, there was no referendum
президент это делать референдума не
A In the ninety-third year,
проводилось А В девяносто третьем году
as you yourself
Как вы сами
said in the Communist Party, almost everyone
сказали в Компартии чуть ли не все
voted that it was not worth
проголосовали за то что не стои было
doing this,
этого делать его
that Crimea belongs by right to
что Крым принадлежит по праву
Russia, they were removed from it, yes, he shot
России их убрали из это да он расстрелял
your parliament Yes, he shot it, got it  and
парламент ваш Да расстрелял о Понято и
to this day, here is Yeltsin’s decree on
до сих пор вот указ Ельцина о
the annexation of Crimea, no one, neither Medvedev nor
присоединении Крыма никто ни Медведев ни
Putin,
Путин
has denounced
ни денонсировала вот реально указ
Yeltsin’s decree on the transfer of Crimea to Ukraine, and it’s
Ельцина о передаче Крыма Украине да до
still in effect. That’s why Putin won’t
сих пор действующий Вот почему Путин не
take it and he couldn’t, he couldn’t have
возьмёт и не он не мог бы он не мог
acted initially, how could he have
действовать изначально как мог
acted if  the people the people didn’t ask at all if they
действовать если народа народ вообще не
wanted it, the people
спросили хочет он этого не хочет люди
living in Crimea didn’t want it. They should have
проживающие в Крыму Они что должны были
just batted their eyes said Oh,
просто глазками похлопать сказал Ой
let’s move on. Oh, wait, well, look,
Давайте перейдём Да ну подожди Ну смотри
look, Yeltsin signed a decree in the ninety-third
Ну смотри Ельцин В девяносто третьем
year, that’s what
году подписал указ он так называется
the decree is called, and the front page, do you remember what it
указ а переда ты помнишь как она
was called?  part of Russia In the ninety-
называлась в составе России В девяносто
third year, Crimea What was the name of the
третьем году Крым Как назывался
Autonomous Republic or the Crimean
Автономная Республика или Крымская
region
область
was well, what was it
была ну как он
called the Autonomous Republic Yes, Crimea
назывался Автономная Республика Да Крым
was part of Russia In the ninety-third
был в составе России В девяносто третьем
year, a republic or a
году республикой или
region a region most likely a region
областью областью скорее всего областью
correctly and Yeltsin signed a decree, it’s
правильно и Ельцин подписал указ он так
called a Presidential Decree  Russian
и называется Указ Президента Российской
Federation Boris Yeltsin about the transfer of the
Федерации Бориса Ельцина о передаче
Crimean region to Ukraine, it was
Крымской области Украине это было 27
July 27, 1993, I
июля девяносто третьего года я это точно
remember it for sure because July 27 is my
помню потому что 27 июля у меня день
birthday, that’s why I remembered it
рождения я на это я поэтому вот запомнил
right there, it was
прямо был
happy with us then. I remember we were sitting,
у нас тогда радовало Я помню мы сидели
I was 12 years old then.  I was
мне было тогда 12 лет Я восемьдесят
born in 1881 and we were celebrating and
первого года рождения и мы праздновали и
dad comes in and talks about Yeltsin handing over
папа заходит говорит о Ельцин передал
Crimea to Ukraine and we are like hurray hurray
Крым Украине и мы короче такие ура ура у
we now have Ukraine will have a new
нас теперь у Украины будет новая
Autonomous Republic like this,
Автономная Республика типа вот так что
but he passed it on, passed it on,
Но он же передал передал нигде в судах
never disputed it in the UN courts, the Crimeans either  they
ООН не оспаривал это крымчане тоже они
got everything In the ninety-third year,
получили все В девяносто третьем году
when Crimea was handed over to Ukraine, the Crimeans
когда Крым передали Украине крымчане
half all had a Ukrainian passport, everyone
полу все паспорт украинский все
agreed. If they were against, they would
согласились Если б они были против они
not have received a Ukrainian passport.
бы не получили паспорт Украины
True, they went to a rally, no one even
Правда они вышли на митинг никто даже не
did a rally against Yeltsin, that he
митинг делал против Ельцина что он
handed over Crimea to Ukraine and that A A  It
передал Крым Украине и что А А смысл это
made sense to do this if at that time the CIS already
было делать если уже на тот момент СНГ
existed, I don’t remember how many years, how
существовал уже не помню сколько лет как
and what Ukraine and Belarus were the
и что Украина что Беларусь являлись
main allied states, this
основными союзными государствами это
was as it should in theory be even
было так как должно по идее быть даже на
today, yes yes Well, look,
сегодняшний день да да Ну смотри
it turns out, look, Yeltsin signed a decree in
получается смотри Ельцин подписал указ В
ninety-three  year on the transfer of Crimea to
девяносто третьем году о передаче Крыма
Ukraine, the decree is in force Yes, the parliament did
Украине указ действующий Да парламент
n’t do anything, yes the parliament Yeltsin
ээ ничего не сделал да парламент Ельцин
shot the parliament, dispersed and made a
расстрелял парламент разогнал и сделал
new one, made a new Constitution, new everything,
новый сделал новую Конституцию новое всё
that is,
то есть до сих пор до 2024 года
Yeltsin’s decree is still in effect until 2024 if you go,
действует указ Ельцина если ты зайдёшь
yes you have Yes, it cannot act
да у вас есть Да он не может действовать
he didn’t have, you know, he essentially had
он не имел знаете он имел по сути
a basis But damn, how could he
основание Но блин как Как он мог
have acted from the very beginning? Well, let
изначально действовать Хорошо пусть там
at least 10 of his signatures be there for the
хоть 10 его подписей будет стоять
referendum, let me
референдума смот ещё раз ещё раз
explain again, look, yes, you have a portal where
объясняю смотри есть да у вас портал где
all state documents
все государственные документы
are published and it’s still hanging there  as a
публикуются и до сих пор там Висит как
valid document, the decree of Boris. The decree of
действующий документ указ Бориса Указ
the President. I remember how it was. The decree of the
Президента Я помню как он Указ
President of the Russian Federation Boris
Президента Российской Федерации Бориса
Yeltsin on the transfer of the Crimean region to
Ельцина о передаче Крымской области
Ukraine on July 27,
Украине 27 июля
1993, decree number 1488, it was
1993 года указ номер 1488 он так был
signed like this. Here you can look. It is
подписан Вот и э ты можешь посмотреть Он
still listed in your
до сих пор у вас числится в вашем
legislation as  no one has
законодательстве как действующий никто
canceled it, and the Constitutional Court has
его не отменил и не Конституционный Суд
not declared it unconstitutional. That is, it is
не признал его неконституционным То есть
logical, but how can you cancel something that was
логич а как можно Отменить то что не по
not supposed to act from the very
идее не могло действовать с самого
beginning, so who Look, you know what a
начала так кто Смотри вот ты знаешь что
constitutional court is,
такое конституционный суд у
so according to the Constitution of the Soviet
вас так по Конституции ещё Советского
Union, Crimea  it was impossible for the World War II to be over, it wasn’t already, it’s a
Союза Крым нельзя было вчм всё уже не
child, it’s not the Soviet
было это же дет год это уже не Советский
Union anymore, it’s been the third year of the Soviet Union,
Союз дено Трей год уже Советского Союза
2 years gone, Yeltsin decides to transfer Crimea
2 года нет Ельцин решает передать Крым
[laughter]
[смех]
to Ukraine
Украине
Yaki give me I appreciate the like squeak comment
Яки дай ты Я доржу лайк писка комент
damn dude, of course he’s handsome like By
блин чувак конечно красава типа По
what right do I  he was thinking right now Yeltsin
какому праву Я думал он сечас Ельцин
conveyed It’s a pity that the guy lost even
передал Жалко что тип сорвался ещё
a little bit of content, we’re from him Well, write to my
трошки контента мы с него Ну пись на мий
Telegram right now axis VN
Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
apok more and more respectfully YouTube borrowing
апок дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through skarg or in your ban and I do
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
n’t show too many videos to people often don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about  Stream Tomu for this purpose,
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
we need to write a Mali operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
right now and while there in telegra
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm video schezh tsikava and korisna
окм видео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we are guilty of you trimati
информация и мы повинни з вами тримати
postiyny operational link
постийний оперативный звязок
independantly in that chi show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Slava Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
write N
пиши N